Kashif Ur Rahman

Web Developer

≥ kashiikhan377@gmail.com

4 0343-9816005

• Rawalpindi, Pakistan

in linkedin.com/in/kashif-ur-rahman-662132207/

Profile

Having Bachelor of science in Software Engineering (BSSE) with almost 6-months professional experience in Programming Languages and Software Engineering. Expert in Web development & Web designing using the MERN Stack technology, Proficient in Front-end and Back-end programming languages, Database management, and software design.

Education

- Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering (BSSE) Gomal University Dera Ismail Khan, Pakistan (2019-2023)
- DIT (Khyber Pakhtunkhwa Board of Technical Education (KPBTE) (2018-2019)

Skills

- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS
- React JS
- MongoDB

- JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery
- Node JS, Express JS
- Problem Solving

Professional Experience

Universal Service Fund - Islamabad (USF) (April 2024- October 2024)

Web Developer Intern (Present)

- Developed Responsive web interfaces using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React JS.
- Collaborated on front-end development projects.
- Assisted in website optimization for speed and scalability.
- Debugged and resolved issues across multiple web applications.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to deliver project milestones.

Eziline Software House Pvt Ltd – Rawalpindi (June 2023- September 2023)

MERN Stack Intern

- Developed and maintained full-stack web applications using MERN Stack.
- Collaborated on front-end and back-end tasks to deliver user-centric features.
- Optimized application performance and enhanced responsiveness.
- Implemented RESTful APIs for seamless client-server communication.
- Participated in code reviews and collaborated in an Agile environment.

Projects

- i. Online Shoe Zone (FYP)
- ii. BUILDNOX Website
- iii. KARMA Website
- iv. School Management System
- v. Resume Builder
- vi. Portfolio Builder
- vii. Online Shopping Centre
- viii. Expense Tracker

E-Commerce Website Online Shoe Zone (FYP)

- Developed an E-Commerce platform for buying and selling shoes using the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js).
- Designed an engaging and User-friendly interface with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Created a dynamic and responsive Front-End with React.js for an intuitive User Experience.
- Implemented a robust Back-End server using Node.js and Express.js for secure and efficient client-database connections.
- Utilized MongoDB for seamless data storage and retrieval.
- Enhanced problem-solving skills by tackling real-world web application development challenges.

LANGUAGE SKILLS:

• English: Good

Urdu: Good Pashto: Good